Guide to the H. G. Merriam Papers 1890-1980
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- University of Montana, 1919-1979; Series V; 1.5 linear feet and partial oversize box
  - Montana Study Documents and Rockefeller Foundation Grant, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Montana Study Documents and Rockefeller Foundation Grant, 1945 (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Official Correspondence, University President Ernest Melby, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Curriculum Committee, Documents and Correspondence, 1943-1945 and 1961 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Official Correspondence, University President James McCain, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Correspondence, University president candidates, 1941, 1945, 1958 (Box-folder 8/3)
  - "History of the Classroom Building", 1950 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Architectural Drawings, Campus buildings (drawn by Merriam), undated (Box-folder 40OS/3)
  - Divisional Reorganization of University Departments, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Correspondence, Search for university positions, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Correspondence, Retirement, 1954 (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Lucia Mirrielees Memorial Fund, Correspondence, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Lucia Mirrielees Memorial, Administrative Papers, 1957-1973 (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Friends of the University Library, 1960-1977 (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Clippings, President Harry Newburn Resignation, 1963 (Box-folder 8/11)
  - University of Montana Press Committee Documents, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 8/12)
  - Edmund Freeman Memorial Fund, Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Edmund Freeman Memorial Fund, Administrative Papers, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 8/14)
- Frontier and Midland, 1921-1973; Series VI; 5.0 linear feet
  The materials in this series include correspondence, draft article and short story manuscripts, and publication materials from the Frontier and Midland journal. The Frontier and Midland is recognized as the first regularly published literary anthology for Montana and the Northern Rocky Mountain region. Materials in the series record Merriam's commitment to establishing and promoting standards for folklore collection, editing, source acknowledgement, and publication. The series includes numerous submissions and sequences of correspondence between Merriam and Montana and Western authors, including Struthers Burt, Grace Stone Coates, Vardis Fisher, Helen Addison Howard, Dorothy Johnson, Frank Bird Linderman, Bob Marshall, Ezra Pound, and Paul Tracy.
  - General Contributors, A-B, 1928-1938 (Box-folder 9/1)
  - General Contributors, C-D, 1928-1949 (Box-folder 9/2)
  - General Contributors, E-G, 1928-1938 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - General Contributors, H-J, 1928-1947 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - General Contributors, K-L, 1923-1942 (Box-folder 9/5)
  - General Contributors, M-N, 1927-1945 (Box-folder 9/6)
  - General Contributors, O-R, 1928-1938 (Box-folder 9/7)
  - General Contributors, S, 1928-1939 (Box-folder 9/8)
  - General Contributors, T-Z, 1928-1941 (Box-folder 9/9)
  - General Contributors, Montana Writers, 1927-1947 (Box-folder 9/10)
  - General Contributors, Anderson, Paul, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 10/1)
  - General Contributors, Appel, Benjamin, 1939 (Box-folder 10/2)
  - General Contributors, Bair, Tom, 1934-1939 (Box-folder 10/3)
  - General Contributors, Barrows, John R., 1930-1935 (Box-folder 10/4)
  - General Contributors, Beebe, Beatrice B. in regard to Joaquin Miller material, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 10/5)
  - General Contributors, Bolles, Jason, 1927-1944 (Box-folder 10/6)
  - General Contributors, Bright, Verne, 1928-1937 (Box-folder 10/7)
  - General Contributors, Campbell, W.S., 1930-1945 (Box-folder 10/8)
  - General Contributors, Chittock, Dr. V.L.O., 1930-1948 (Box-folder 10/9)
  - General Contributors, Burt, Struthers, 1931-1936 (Box-folder 10/10)
  - General Contributors, Coates, Grace Stone, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 10/11)
  - General Contributors, Coates, Grace Stone, 1930-1934 (Box-folder 10/12)
  - General Contributors, Coates, Grace Stone, 1935-1947 (Box-folder 10/13)
  - General Contributors, Corning, Howard, 1928-1939, 1969 (Box-folder 11/1)
  - General Contributors, Davis, H.L., 1927-1938 (Box-folder 11/2)
  - General Contributors, Driggs, Hal, 1932-1948 (Box-folder 11/3)
  - General Contributors, Eldridge, Paul, 1934-1937, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 11/4)
  - General Contributors, Elmendorf, Mrs. M.J., 1929-1936 (Box-folder 11/5)
  - General Contributors, Ernest, Mrs. Alice Henson, 1929-1938 (Box-folder 11/6)
  - General Contributors, Fisher, Vardis, 1931-1936 (Box-folder 11/7)
  - General Contributors, Fitzgerald, Bob, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 11/8)
  - General Contributors, Fuller, Mrs. E. Romig, 1928-1933 (Box-folder 11/9)
  - General Contributors, Garcia, Andrew, 1930 (Box-folder 11/10)
  - General Contributors, Gearhart, Edna, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 11/11)
  - General Contributors, Godchaux, Elma, 1932-1938 (Box-folder 11/12)
  - General Contributors, Goodpasture, Frank G., 1930-1937 (Box-folder 11/13)
  - General Contributors, Grisson, Irene Welch, 1928-1931 (Box-folder 11/14)
  - General Contributors, Hansen, Joe, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 11/15)
  - General Contributors, Hare, John, 1928 (Box-folder 11/16)
  - General Contributors, Hartley, Ronald English, 1928-1939 (Box-folder 11/17)
  - General Contributors, Hartwick, Mrs. Mary Robert, 1928-1941 (Box-folder 11/18)
  - General Contributors, Haste, Gwendolen, 1928-1933 (Box-folder 11/19)
  - General Contributors, Haycox, Ernest, 1932 (Box-folder 11/20)
  - General Contributors, Hilton, Charles, 1927-1934 (Box-folder 11/21)
  - General Contributors, Hogan, Steve, 1927-1931 (Box-folder 12/1)
  - General Contributors, Holbrook, Stewart, 1936-1951 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - General Contributors, Hulbert, Archer B., 1928-1933 (Box-folder 12/3)
  - General Contributors, Huse, Harry G., 1928-1931 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - General Contributors, James, Will, 1928-1931 (Box-folder 12/5)
  - General Contributors, Johnson, Dorothy M., 1927-1950 (Box-folder 12/6)
  - General Contributors, Jones, Nard, 1930-1948 (Box-folder 12/7)
  - General Contributors, Kidd, W.E., 1928-1936 (Box-folder 12/8)
  - General Contributors, Kizer, Ben and M. Ashley, 1927-1930 (Box-folder 12/9)
  - General Contributors, Knight, Chatfield, 1930-1932 (Box-folder 12/10)
  - General Contributors, Krantz, David E., 1935-1936 (Box-folder 12/11)
  - General Contributors, Lake, Richard, 1935-1963 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - General Contributors, Leeper, Robert D., 1929-1932 (Box-folder 12/13)
  - General Contributors, Lister, Queene B., 1928-1932, 1937 (Box-folder 12/14)
  - General Contributors, Loux, Martha D. (material on Abraham Lincoln), 1929-1930 (Box-folder 12/15)
  - General Contributors, MacLeod, Norman, 1928-1929, 1936 (Box-folder 12/16)
  - General Contributors, Maring, Helen, 1929-1932, 1938 (Box-folder 12/17)
  - General Contributors, McWilliams, Carey, 1930-1963 (Box-folder 12/18)
  - General Contributors, Marshall, Jim, 1928-1946 (Box-folder 13/1)
  - General Contributors, Marshall, Robert, 1929-1934, 1937 (Box-folder 13/2)
  - General Contributors, Mathews, Courtland, 1928-1943 (Box-folder 13/3)
  - General Contributors, Merrill, Arthur T., 1928-1936 (Box-folder 13/4)
  - General Contributors, Olson, Ted, 1927-1936 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - General Contributors, Pendray, G. Edward, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 13/6)
  - General Contributors, Post, Mary, 1929-1932 (Box-folder 13/7)
  - General Contributors, Pratt, L.L, 1929-1935 (Box-folder 13/8)
  - General Contributors, Redington, J.W., 1931-1933 (Box-folder 13/9)
  - General Contributors, Robinson, Mrs. C.D., 1920-1930 (Box-folder 13/10)
  - General Contributors, Rorty, James, 1929-1932 (Box-folder 13/11)
  - General Contributors, Rushfelt, Elise, 1928-1942 (Box-folder 13/12)
  - General Contributors, Sarett, Lew, 1925-1938 (Box-folder 13/13)
  - General Contributors, Smith, Bess Foster, 1927-1931 (Box-folder 13/14)
  - General Contributors, Spencer, Lillian White, 1927-1932 (Box-folder 13/15)
  - General Contributors, Stevens, James, 1927-1948 (Box-folder 13/16)
  - General Contributors, Stewart, George R., 1932-1935 (Box-folder 13/17)
  - General Contributors, Sweetman, Luke, 1928-1934, 1940-1946 (Box-folder 13/18)
  - General Contributors, Terrell, John Upton, 1929-1936 (Box-folder 14/1)
  - General Contributors, Thomas, E.H., 1928-1931 (Box-folder 14/2)
  - General Contributors, Tracy, Paul E., 1928-1939, 1963 (Box-folder 14/3)
  - General Contributors, Tucker, Pat J., 1921-1930 (Box-folder 14/4)
  - General Contributors, Vontuer, Mrs. May, 1928-1932, 1941-1942, 1946 (Box-folder 14/5)
    1970
  - General Contributors, Wetjen, Richard, 1928-1938 (Box-folder 14/6)
  - General Contributors, Wickes, Mrs. T.A., 1930-1932 (Box-folder 14/7)
  - General Contributors, Worthen, Clifton B., 1928-1931 (Box-folder 14/8)
  - General Contributors, undated (Box-folder 14/9)
  - General Correspondence, A-C, 1928-1962 (Box-folder 14/10)
  - General Correspondence, D-G, 1920-1958 (Box-folder 14/11)
  - General Correspondence, H-M, 1927-1939 (Box-folder 14/12)
  - General Correspondence, N-Z, 1923-1945 (Box-folder 14/13)
  - General Correspondence, Botkin, B.A. and Folk-Say magazine, 1929-1937 (Box-folder 15/1)
  - General Correspondence, Branch, E. Douglas, 1936-1962 (Box-folder 15/2)
  - General Correspondence, Clark, Archie, Great Falls Tribune, 1937-1943 (Box-folder 15/3)
  - General Correspondence, Cox, Sidney, in regard to finances and other University affairs, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 15/4)
  - General Correspondence, Cox, Sidney, in regard to his resignation, 1926 (Box-folder 15/5)
  - General Correspondence, Frederick, John T., in regard to merging The Frontier and The Midland, 1928-1938 (Box-folder 15/6)
  - General Correspondence, Hebard, Dr. Grace Raymond, University of Wyoming, 1927-1932 (Box-folder 15/7)
  - General Correspondence, Howard, Helen Addison, 1939-1944 (Box-folder 15/8)
  - General Correspondence, Linderman, Frank B., 1927-1930 (Box-folder 15/9)
  - General Correspondence, Linderman, Frank B., 1931-1939, 1942, 1952 (Box-folder 15/10)
  - General Correspondence, Peterson, Martin, 1928-1931, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 15/11)
  - General Correspondence, Pound, Ezra, 1931-1934 (Box-folder 15/12)
  - General Correspondence, Sedgwick, Ellery, Atlantic Monthly, 1928-1930, 1947 (Box-folder 15/13)
  - General Correspondence, Wagner, Har, in regard to Joaquin Miller material, 1932 (Box-folder 15/14)
  - General Correspondence, Whicker, H., UM English professor and Frontier editor, 1934-1939 (Box-folder 15/15)
  - General Correspondence, Historical Maps, 1929-1934 (Box-folder 16/1)
  - General Correspondence, Historical Maps, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 16/2)
  - General Correspondence, Historical Material, 1929-1933 (Box-folder 16/3)
  - General Correspondence, Sale of back issues, 1928, 1952-1971 (Box-folder 16/4)
  - General Correspondence, Sale of back issues with regard to The Frontier and Midland Award, 1948-1979 (Box-folder 16/5)
  - General Correspondence, Requests and grants to reprint, 1928-1941 (Box-folder 16/6)
  - General Correspondence, Requests and grants to reprint, 1942-1957 (Box-folder 16/7)
  - General Correspondence, Requests and grants to reprint, 1958-1972, 1975, 1977 (Box-folder 16/8)
  - Advertising, 1934 (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Bonds, 1924-1950 (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Books, possible from Frontier material, 1966 and undated (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Clippings, 1921-1930 (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Clippings, 1932-1938 (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Clippings, undated (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Contributions and Circulation, statistics, up to August 1931 (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Doubleday, Doran, and Co. regarding magazine name and books, 1924-1950 (Box-folder 17/8)
  - Editors of other magazines, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 17/9)
  - Editors of other magazines, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 17/10)
  - Editors of other magazines, 1931-1934 (Box-folder 17/11)
  - Fort Missoula Records, 1935, 1947 (Box-folder 17/12)
  - Folklore, 1930-1933 (Box-folder 17/13)
  - Gipson, J.H., Caxton Printers, 1930-1942 (Box-folder 17/14)
  - Glick, Carl, The Masquers and finances, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 17/15)
  - Knopf, Alfred A., Borzoi Books Inc. Publisher, 1930-1948 (Box-folder 17/16)
  - League of Western Writers, list of (Box-folder 17/17)
  - Linderman, Frank B. issue, spring 1938-1939 (Box-folder 17/18)
  - Macmillan Co., Publishers, 1936-1942 (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Magazine exchanges, undated (Box-folder 18/2)
  - Mailing, 2nd class, 1928-1933 (Box-folder 18/3)
  - Mailing Lists, Universities and Colleges, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Merriam's notes on The Frontier, history, 1930-1965 (Box-folder 18/5)
  - N.Y. Public Library microfilming, 1964, 1973 (Box-folder 18/6)
  - O'Brien, E.J., Editor, 'Best Short Stories', 1927-1935 (Box-folder 18/7)
  - O'Henry Collection of Stories, 1929-1937 (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Pacific Spectator, 1946 (Box-folder 18/9)
  - Periodical Information, 1928 (Box-folder 18/10)
  - Prairie Schooner, 1929-1934 (Box-folder 18/11)
  - Publishers, 1930-1947 (Box-folder 18/12)
  - Ratings, O'Brien and O'Henry, 1928-1939 (Box-folder 18/13)
  - Reestablishing The Frontier, 1938-1947 (Box-folder 18/14)
  - Reprinting (Johnson Reprint Co. and Kraus Reprint Co.), 1966-1967, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 18/15)
  - Sample Literature to subscribers, 1927-1936 (Box-folder 18/16)
  - Short Stories, undated (Box-folder 18/17)
  - Stationery and Publicity, 1920-1943 (Box-folder 18/18)
  - Suspension of The Frontier, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 18/19)
  - Title use: The Frontier and The Midland by other magazines, 1934-1944 (Box-folder 18/20)
  - Trademark Application, 1924-1949 (Box-folder 18/21)
  - Notecards, Subscriptions and Contributors to Frontier and Midland (Box-folder File box/19)
- Montana Institute of the Arts, 1941-1980; Series VII; 2.25 linear feet
  This series includes materials generated and collected by Merriam during his tenure with the Montana Institute of the Arts. Series documents detail efforts to establish and expand the organization as a grassroots arts and humanities program in the state. The Montana Institute of the Arts helped create avenues for fostering and promoting artistic expression by Montanans who often lacked access to the established outlets.
  Materials are arranged by subject, then chronologically.
  - General Correspondence, 1948-1976 (Box-folder 20/1)
  - General Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 20/2)
  - General Correspondence, Early Letters, 1941, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 20/3)
  - General Correspondence, Pre-organizational, 1941-1949 (Box-folder 20/4)
  - General Correspondence, Organizational, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 20/5)
  - General Correspondence, Organization, 1957-1976 (Box-folder 20/6)
  - General Correspondence, Merriam's first year of presidency, 1948-March, 1949 (Box-folder 20/7)
  - General Correspondence, Merriam's first year of presidency, March 16, 1949-August 1949 (Box-folder 20/8)
  - General Correspondence, Presidents and Secretaries, 1955-1966, 1971 (Box-folder 20/9)
  - General Correspondence, Finch, Robert, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 21/1)
  - General Correspondence, Grieder, Paul A., 1946-1950 (Box-folder 21/2)
  - General Correspondence, Stevenson, Branson, Christmas Cards, 1948, 1968-1979 (Box-folder 21/3)
  - General Correspondence, MIA Book, General MIA information, 1976 (Box-folder 21/4)
  - General Correspondence, MIA Book, List of Articles and Organization, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 21/5)
  - General Correspondence, MIA Book, Permission to use articles, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 21/6)
  - General Correspondence, MIA Book, Requests to select articles, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 21/7)
  - General Correspondence, MIA Book, Finances and Publication, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 21/8)
  - General Correspondence, MIA Book, Finalizing, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 21/9)
  - General Correspondence, Publishing Projects Quarterly, 1949-1956, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 21/10)
  - General Correspondence, Poetry Contests and Booklets, 1956, 1961-1966, 1980 (Box-folder 21/11)
  - General Correspondence, First Poetry Book, Seed in the Soil, MIA Poets, 1966-1968, 1973 (Box-folder 21/12)
  - General Correspondence, Second Poetry Book, 1973 (Box-folder 21/13)
  - General Correspondence, Headquarters and Buildings, 1962, 1965, 1977 (Box-folder 22/1)
  - General Correspondence, Rental of Pictures, Reader's Alley Art Gallery, 1963 (Box-folder 22/2)
  - General Correspondence, Restructuring MIA, 1965-1966, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 22/3)
  - General Correspondence, Sale of MIA craft projects, 1950 (Box-folder 22/4)
  - General Correspondence, Short Story project, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 22/5)
  - General Correspondence, Writers, Joseph Kinsey Howard, Fox, and Place, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 22/6)
  - General Correspondence, Young Montana Artist Show, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 22/7)
  - Branch Directors' Meetings, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 22/8)
  - Communication Information for officers, etc., 1971-1976 (Box-folder 22/9)
  - Constitution and By Laws, 1948-1968 (Box-folder 22/10)
  - Disassociated Documents, 1948-1977 (Box-folder 22/11)
  - Expanding Montana Historical Society, 1949 (Box-folder 22/12)
  - Festival Features, 1976 (Box-folder 22/13)
  - Festival Programs, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 22/14)
  - Foundation, 1957, 1961-1966 (Box-folder 22/15)
  - Foundation, History, 1961 (Box-folder 22/16)
  - Foundation, Incorporation, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 22/17)
  - Foundation, 1967-1969, 1972, 1976 (Box-folder 22/18)
  - History Group, 1949 (Box-folder 22/19)
  - Little Festival, 1962, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 22/20)
  - Membership and Affiliations, 1949, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 22/21)
  - Membership Certificates, 1949 (Box-folder 22/22)
  - Membership Lists, 1948-1970 (Box-folder 22/23)
  - MIA Book, extras, 1975 or 1976 (Box-folder 23/1)
  - MIA Book, cutout, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 23/2)
  - MIA Leadership Workshop, September 1979 (Box-folder 23/3)
  - Minutes, Board, 1962-1963, 1969-1976, 1979 (Box-folder 23/4)
  - Minutes of Directors, 1948-1957 (Box-folder 23/5)
  - Montana Arts Council, 1963-1975 (Box-folder 23/6)
  - Newsletters, 1963-1966, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 23/7)
  - Permanent Collection, 1955-1970 (Box-folder 23/8)
  - Poetry Contest, Mary B. Clapp Memorial, 1966-May 1968 (Box-folder 23/9)
  - Poetry Contest, Mary B. Clapp Memorial, 1968-1968, 1976, 1979 (Box-folder 23/10)
  - Poem about Merriam, 1973 (Box-folder 23/11)
  - Presidential Address to MIA, 1950 (Box-folder 24/1)
  - Publicity, 1948-1962 (Box-folder 24/2)
  - Quarterly, Costs and Articles, 1948-1964 (Box-folder 24/3)
  - Roundup of the Arts, Gallery Museum Facility, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 24/4)
  - Speakers for Workshops, 1950, 1952 (Box-folder 24/5)
  - Treasurer Reports, 1949-1977 (Box-folder 24/6)
  - Clippings, MIA, 1947-1977 (Box-folder 24/7)
  - Clippings, Montana Artists, 1961-1966 (Box-folder 24/8)
- Writings, 1902-1980; Series VIII; 5.5 linear feet
  This series includes correspondence, draft manuscripts, hand-written notes, and publication materials from the documents Merriam wrote himself or edited to such an extent they became, in essence, his own work. The series provides insights into Merriam's multi-faceted literary projects as well as his influence on contemporaries. The Moxon manuscript and correspondence materials include correspondence with Moxon's descendents as well as some of the most notable English literary figures of the mid 19th Century.
  Materials are arranged by subject or by title of book-length publication.
  - Apologia for Creative Writing, undated (Box-folder 25/1)
  - Address to the Soc. Conference-Seattle, Washington, undated (Box-folder 25/2)
  - Clippings about writings of other authors, undated (Box-folder 25/3)
  - Creative Writing-manuscript for Writer's Conference, undated (Box-folder 25/4)
  - Essay, Ideas, undated (Box-folder 25/5)
  - Favorite Words, undated (Box-folder 25/6)
  - Memories of My Days at the University of Wyoming, 1902-1904, undated (Box-folder 25/7)
  - Misc. Writings, undated (Box-folder 25/8)
  - Montana History Research, undated (Box-folder 25/9)
  - Montana Writers, undated (Box-folder 25/10)
  - Northwest Theaters-articles, undated (Box-folder 25/11)
  - Research Notes found in the works of Spencer, undated (Box-folder 25/12)
  - Stories of Pacific Northwest in Verse, undated (Box-folder 25/13)
  - These Men Have Been in Our Home-manuscript, undated (Box-folder 25/14)
  - They Worked in the West-manuscript, undated (Box-folder 25/15)
  - They Worked in the West-manuscript, undated (Box-folder 25/16)
  - Western Literature-What's it and Why-manuscript and notes, undated (Box-folder 25/17)
  - Inhibitions, Habits and the Student's Right of Way-article, 1918 (Box-folder 25/18)
  - Report on the University of Montana, 1920-1930 (Box-folder 25/19)
  - Class Book for Freshman Composition, 1921 (Box-folder 25/20)
  - Unsuccessful Articles, 1925-1948 (Box-folder 26/1)
  - Edward Moxon Manuscript, correspondence, 1925-10 - 1926-06 (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Edward Moxon Manuscript, correspondence, 1926-07 - 1938-01 (Box-folder 26/3)
  - Edward Moxon, Publisher of Poets, Reviews and Notices, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 26/4)
  - Western Regional Literature-research, notes, and correspondence, 1929-1949 (Box-folder 26/5)
  - The Idea of a Regional College Magazine-article, 1928-04-11 (Box-folder 26/6)
  - Regional Literature-presentation, 1929-11-29 (Box-folder 26/7)
  - Northwest Writers, 1930's (Box-folder 26/8)
  - Unpublished Manuscript for Book, no title (Box-folder 26/9)
  - Unpublished Manuscript for Book, no title (Box-folder 26/10)
  - Unpublished Manuscript for Book, no title (Box-folder 26/11)
  - Northwest Verse: A Note-manuscript, 1930's (Box-folder 26/12)
  - Anthology of Northwest Verse-correspondences (permission to reprint), 1930 (Box-folder 27/1)
  - Anthology of Northwest Verse-correspondences (permission to reprint), 1931-1932 (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Anthology of Northwest Verse-reviews, 1931 (Box-folder 27/3)
  - Anthology of Northwest Verse-reviews in newspapers clippings, 1931 (Box-folder 27/4)
  - Regionalism-manuscript for Writer's Conference-U.M., 1931 (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Northwest Literature-presentation to PNLA, 1934 (Box-folder 27/6)
  - Tamress in Northwest Writers and Readers-article, 1935 (Box-folder 27/7)
  - Works Projects Administration Writers Project-correspondence, 1935-1969 (Box-folder 27/8)
  - The Liberal Arts-address to the University of Oregon, 1936 (Box-folder 27/9)
  - Liberal Arts College in State Supported University-article, 1936-11-03 (Box-folder 27/10)
  - Baccalaureate Address-Reed College, 1937 (Box-folder 27/11)
  - Address at the Modern Language Assoc., Contemporary Literature Section, 1937 (Box-folder 27/12)
  - Literature and the Liberal Arts College-presentation at the University of Oregon, 1939 (Box-folder 27/13)
  - Radio Addresses at Oregon State College, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 27/14)
  - Radio Addresses at KGVO radio, Missoula Montana, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 27/15)
  - In Measureless Oceans-presentation, 1940 (Box-folder 28/1)
  - Cosmos Club-Constitution (copy), 1896-1897 (Box-folder 28/2)
  - Club Papers-Cosmos Club, 1940-1972 (Box-folder 28/3)
  - Club Papers-English, Authors, and MIA, undated (Box-folder 28/4)
  - Materials for American Literary History-introduction and correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 28/5)
  - Ethnic Settlement in Montana-notes and research, 1942 (Box-folder 28/6)
  - Ethnic Settlement in Montana-manuscript and article, 1943 (Box-folder 28/7)
  - Book Reviews-articles and manuscripts, 1943-1953 (Box-folder 28/8)
  - An Experiment in Education-pamphlet, 1945-05 (Box-folder 28/9)
  - Writing in High School-article, 1945-12 (Box-folder 28/10)
  - Northwest Literature in Our Schools-presentation, 1946-11-16 (Box-folder 28/11)
  - Folk Materials in Montana, 1946 (Box-folder 28/12)
  - Regional Cooperation in Higher Education, 1946, 1951, 1965 (Box-folder 28/13)
  - Reilly Was Here-article, 1947 (Box-folder 28/14)